You may have seen this demo where you
put several metronomes on a light wobbly
platform and start them out of sync.
These metronomes don't have exactly the
same natural frequency, and yet they
still beat in time.
>> [clears throat]
>> To understand how this works, it's
easiest to first consider a couple
metronomes oscillating in sync with each
other. When the large masses accelerate
to the left, they push the platform to
the right. And when they accelerate to
the right, they push the platform to the
left. So, the center of mass of the
system always stays roughly in the same
spot.
Now, if you start another metronome
completely out of sync with the first
two, the motion of the platform gives it
a kick every half swing, speeding it up
until it's in time with the first two.
>> [music]
>> This works regardless of the number of
metronomes you have.
>> [music]
>> The platform just goes whichever way the
majority of metronomes are pushing it.